Guide to the Philip Whalen Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Poems and Manuscripts,1941-1971
  - Raging Desire &c., 1963 September 27 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Real San Francisco Sunday Afternoon, 1961 April 22 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Reason Why, 1941 January 31 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - A Recall, 1963 November 25 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - A reflection of her face ..., 1941 March 25 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Remembered at Last, 1963 November 17 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Re-take 20:xii 63 from 7: iii: 63, 1963 December 20 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Revolution, June 23, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Revolutionaries, 1961 October 7 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Returned from the mountains, 1957 August 15 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The river in the moonlight …, 1941 March 26 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Road-runner, for L.J. Reynolds, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Robert and Barbara (acrostic) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Robert La Vigne, 1964 March 5 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - A romantic & beautiful poem inspired by the recollection…, 1967 February 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Romanticism & the Modern Ego (summa contra Barzun) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Rondo, 1941 March 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Rotunda Gallery (for W.G.), 1952 January 13 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Roxie Powell, 1963 October 22 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Sad Song, 1965 September 11 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sad Song in the Antique Manner, 1953 November 22 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Saguaro (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - St. Francis Lobbies Allen G., 1963 November 12 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Salamander, 1963 November 23 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Saltwater and iodine ..., 1951 September 30 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco, Goodbye, 1962 October 25 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The San Francisco Morning Palimpsest, 1961 April 23 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sanju Sangendo, 1966 December 28 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sanjusangendo, 1966 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - A satire, 1965 March 12 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Saturday, 1962 September 15 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Saturday Morning, 1961 September 23 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The Saturday Visitations, 1962 November 29 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Saturday's Child has Far to Go, 1966 July 13 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sauced!, 1955 November 6 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Scenes of Life at the Capital,1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Scholiast, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Sealion (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Seal of Melancthon, 1959 July 13 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Second Day of May 1965 1965 March 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Second rate like Schumann or Dvorak ..., 1957 December 10 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Secret, 1965 July 31 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Seen from the parapet above the surf ..., 1952 June 17 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Seven hours afraid … (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Senseless commentaries on Chao-Chou, 1958 March 23 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - A Sermon on the Coming Destruction of Bubbles (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sestina, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Severance Pay,1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 6 to 7)
  - A shift. A change for the better ..., 1962 November 10 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - A Shock, 1964 April 17 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Shock of Recognition (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Shore Scene, 1941 March 11 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Short Explanation of Everything, 1960 July 20 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - A Short History of the Second Millennium B.C., 1962 September 22 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Shut the Cupboard After the Peanut Butter, 1958 July 1 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sincerity Shot, 1958 March 23 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Skoolie-bau, 1965 February 14 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sleeping-bag, 1959 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sleepy, 1965 May 9 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Small Tantric Sermon, 1956 September 17 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - So many of these poems are silence ..., 1963 November 26 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - So much of the world a wonder a beauty to me ..., 1960 July 20 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Social Graces, 1963 September 28 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Somebody Else's Aesthetic, 1963 October 7 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Some Kind of Theory, 1966 September 9 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Some Places, 1963 October 4 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Song, 1964 March 7 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - A Song, 1959 August 14 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Song for 2 Balalaikas on the Corner of 3rd & Market, 1962 November 30 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Song to Begin Rohatsu, 1962 November 30 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Soup of Winter Melon ..., 1965 May 9 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Spider Chrysanthemum, 1954 December 3 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Spring Musick, 1963 February 9 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Spring Night, 1941 February 14 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Spring Poem, 1960 February 4 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Spring Poem to the Memory of Jane Ellen Harrison (1850-1928), 1963 February 18 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Statement of Condition, 1961 October 7 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Staying or Going, 1961 March 2 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The sun has been down ..., 1942 July 27 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The sun rises and sets in that child, 1965 May (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sunday Afternoon Dinner Fung Loy Restaurant San Francisco, 1962 November 25 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sunday, One more cup of coffee ..., 1960 January 11 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Synesthesia, 1966 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - T./O., 1965 May 7 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - A Tack for Uncle William's Chair, 1948 February 19 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Take, 1959 March 25 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - A Take on the Domestic Scene, 1957 June 3 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Takeout, 1957 April 15 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Takes, 1959 March (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Tara, 1965 September 5 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Task Rejected, 1965 September 3 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Technicalities for Jack Spicer, 1964 January 26 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Technology (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Tell Me More, 1954 January 11 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Tell me what's on your mind ..., 1958 April 2 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Temporarily Insane, 1959 September 12 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Temptation of St. Anthony, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Ten Titanic Etudes, for the Virtuoso Executant, 1966 October 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tennis Shoes, 1963 June 28 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - That Eyes! Those Nose!, 1965 July 12 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - That Dream, 1963 September 7 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - That One, 1961 July 10 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Theophany, 1963 December 29 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Theory (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - There is rain in the city ..., [1943] (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - There it goes, 1962 September 13 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - There once was a guy named Beaudouin…, 1941 January 22 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - They appeared to me as I was dying …, 1962 November 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - They have hung …, 1941 January 29 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - They roll across the country …, 1941 January 20 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - They talk about sea-level ..., 1959 September 8 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - They're making another iron suit ..., 1948 July-August (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 31 vii 1965 is the Last day of July, 1965 July 31 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - This is what I think ..., 1941 March 5 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - This without you ..., 1957 October 1 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Thought by a River, 1941 March 12 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Thought on Sunday Eve, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Three Desert Poems, 1948 January 8 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Three Mornings, 1963 July 15 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 3 Pigs & 3 Houses, 1952 June 18 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Three Poems by Philip Whalen, [1954] (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Three …, 1952 January 13 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Three Satires, [1950] (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Through the tangled lace of the elms…, 1941 March 25 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Thursday in Byzantium, February 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Time Poem, 1964 May 8 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Times alone … (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To a Nervous Man, 1963 November 15 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To a Poet, 1959 December 31 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To break through whatever barrier ..., 1956 November 9 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To My Muse, 1964 November 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To Olson, 1957 February 28 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To Robinson Jeffers, 1956 October 30 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To Ruth, 1961 April 29 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To the Critics, 1964 March 25 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To the Lemur, 1941 February 27 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To the Moon, 1959 August 13 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To the Muse, 1962 April 25 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To the Muse, 1963 July 20 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - To Tom Parkinson, 1965 March 4 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Translation of a Lost Play by. M.K., 1958 March 19 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Treasure, 1941 March 6 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Treasure of Heaven, 1963 December 5 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Treasures of Rage, 1961 April 20 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Trinity Sunday, 1954 for WHD, 1964 May 24 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Trip, 1965 October 30 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Trolley, 1966 July 15 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Trying too hard to write a poem ..., 1958 July 12 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Tuesday Survived (Poems), 1948 Summer (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Twin Peaks, 1961 May 11 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Two days of silence ..., 1962 November 1 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Two Miracles (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Ultimatum, 1942 May 6 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Uncle-William's Bed of Nails, 1948 March 21 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Unfinished, 3:xii:55, 1955 July 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Unsuccessful Spring Poem, 1958 May 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Upon the Late Mrs W_____ (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Ushi Katsurim, 1966 October 16 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Vancouver, 1963 August (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Vanilla,1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Variation on a Theme; to R___ T____ on her 1st Anniversary, 1948 March 20 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Vector Analysis, 1961 August 21 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Venetian blinds dissect the sun ..., 1948 Summer (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Vignette of an Ice Axe, 1965 August 1 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - A Vision of the Bodhisattvas, 1960 March 31 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - A Visit, After Many Years, 1952 November (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Visiting (prose),1954-1956 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Voyages (diary notes), 1966 July (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The War Poem for Diane di Prima, 1966 May-August (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Waiting for Claude, 1966 September 6 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Walked between ..., 1963 February 25 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Walkers' Patio Giant Plant, 1963 December 8 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Warnings, Responses, etc., 1960 February 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We forget why we're here … (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We may not be great ..., 1959 March 6 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We of course are unfit ... (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We of the Theater (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We sat with this wall between us ..., 1957 April 23 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We walked together …, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - A Wednesday Morning, 1963 June 24 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - We're all afraid to love each other... 1957 October 4 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - What we want to do ..., 1958 July 12 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - What does it mean ..., 1963 September 29 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - What Finally Happened to the King, 1965 July 19 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - What next ..., 1956 December 10 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - What's it to me …, 1953 April 11 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - When I got home ..., 1957 March 27 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - When you were fairly gone ..., 1963 March 18 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Where was I, 1963 July 26 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - While the Patient Slept, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The whisper of the swishing wind ..., 1941 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Whistler's Mother, 1963 December 14 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - White River Ode, 1966 June 20 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Why/at what (or whom) does the lady smile ..., 1959 February 26 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Why don't you wait and see what happens ..., 1963 July 1 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Why the sheep-herder kicked his dog ..., 1956 October 7 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Winter,1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Winter Jelly, 1963 December 28 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Wishwood Revisited (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - With him ..., 1963 April 31 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Words of Encouragement ..., 1958 February 1 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - World out of Control, 1963 May 10 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Would that these pale hands ..., 1942 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - X, I say, or the pencil writes ..., 1962 August 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Yes, we will go now … 1952 June 15 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - You are locked inside your houses …, 1957 February 13 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - You could have it once ..., 1955 September 29 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - You're too faraway…, 1964 April 27 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - You Didn't Even, Try - a Novel, 1963-1967
    - Holograph Manuscript (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Typescript (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Proofs and Revisions (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Poems and Manuscript,1941-1967 (Box 19, Folder 1 to 22)
- Series III: Publications and Documents,1946-1972
  - Publishers' Catalogs and Event Announcements
    - A-F (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - G-J (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - M-P (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - S-W (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material
    - Matchbook Journal and Joyce Holland Materials,1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - The New Book/A Book of Torture: Poems by Michael McClure (Box 20, Folder 6)
      (annotated by Whalen)
    - Clippings, etc (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Documents
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Gentle Thursday Materials, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Notes for Course Taught at UCLA, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Reed College Material (Transcripts, Theater Programs, etc.),1946-1951 (Folder 11)